Register of the Burnett Bolloten Papers, 1923-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPANISH CIVIL WAR SUBJECT FILE, 1931-1987 (Box 83-102)
  - Trotsky, Leon. Includes material relating to Kurt Landau and Ramon Mercader. Printed interview and writings by Trotsky, letter by Katia Landau, clippings, and printed articles by Earl Browder, Will Herberg, Isaac Don Levine and others, 1936-1986 (Folder 4-5)
  - Union General de Trabajadores (UGT). Conference reports, speeches, clippings, and printed excerpts and interviews by Amaro del Rosal, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Union General de Trabajadores, 1937-1981. (Folder 6)
  - Uprising, Clippings, pamphlet, and printed excerpts and articles, 1936-1976, 1936 July. (Folder 7)
  - Vazquez, Mariano R. Speech by Vazquez, printed interview, clippings, notes, and printed writings by Jesus Hernandez, Andre Marty, and Federica Montseny, 1938-1952 (Folder 8)
  - Vidali, Vittorio (Carlos Contreras). Memorandum and report excerpt by Vidali, typescript interview notes, printed articles and excerpts, and a letter, 1937-1985 (Folder 9)
  - Women. Clippings and printed articles, 1936-1976 (Folder 10)
  - Youth. Clippings (primarily Juventud Libre), flyer, printed articles, and a letter and typescript by Wilebaldo Solano, "La Juventud Comunista Iberica en la Revolucion y la Guerra de Espaia,", 1936-1987 (Folder 11)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1928?-1986 (Box 82-107)
  Reports, correspondence, printed articles, printed excerpts, clippings, flyers, speeches, bulletins, pamphlets, transcripts, notes, press releases and biographical material. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Communism. Clippings and printed excerpts, 1938-1981 (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo (CNT). Clippings, 1950-1980 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Euzkadi (Spain). Bulletin, printed article, and statement by Ramon Ormazabal, 1952-1968 (Folder 2)
  - Latin America. Clippings, testimony transcript, and printed excerpts, 1953-1978 (Folder 3)
  - Malatesta, Errico. Serial issue, 1966 (Folder 4)
  - Partido Comunista de Espaia (PCE). Clippings, pamphlet, printed excerpts and articles by Santiago Carrillo, Enrique Lister and others, and a typescript book review by George Esenwein, 1941-1986 (Folder 5-6)
  - Partido Socialista Obrero Espaiol (PSOE). Clippings, pamphlets, printed excerpts, and speeches and writings by Ramon Lamoneda, Rodolfo Llopis, Juan Negrin, Indalecio Prieto and others, 1928?-1979 (Folder 7)
  - Partit Socialista Unificat de Catalunya (PSUC). Clippings, printed article, and letters by Juan Comorera, 1940-1979 (Folder 8)
  - Soviet Union. Biographical sketches, notes, letter, and printed articles and excerpts
    - Undated (Folder 9)
    - 1938-1969 (Folder 10)
    - 1970-1983 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Spain. Primarily relates to the Franco regime. Clippings, notes, debate transcript, bulletins, printed articles and excerpts, typescript book reviews by Bertram Wolfe and Luis S. Ponce de Leon, and a mimeograph copy of Adolfo Monsanto, "Panorama Politico de la Espaia Contemporanea,", 1940-1988 (Folder 2)
  - Spanish refugees and exiles
    - General. Typescript refugee reports, clippings, typescript copies of correspondence between Indalecio Prieto and Juan Negrin, printed articles and excerpts by Angel Ossorio, Jose Diaz and others, letters by Jay Allen, and a mimeograph copy of "Memorandum on the Attempt to Present Certain Antifascist Refugees as 'the Leaders of the Fifth Column in Latin America,'", 1939-1986 (Folder 3-5)
    - Relief organizations. Bound flyers, bulletins, leaflets, circulars, press releases, and pamphlets, 1937-1940 (Folder 6)
    - Republican government in exile. Printed articles, excerpts, and clippings, 1940-1984 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Tresca, Carlo. Clippings, 1943-1949 (Folder 2)
  - Union General de Trabajadores. Clippings and printed excerpts, 1940-1978 (Folder 3)
  - World politics, Primarily relates to the events leading to World War II, 1933-1945.
    - General. Printed articles and excerpts by Winston Churchill, Anthony Eden and others
      - Undated (Folder 4)
      - 1938-1962 (Folder 5-7)
      - 1963-1976 (Box 106, Folder 1-6)
      - 1977-1985 (Box 107, Folder 1-3)
    - Diplomatic documents
      - France. Printed copies of diplomatic messages, 1939 (Folder 4)
      - Germany. Printed copies of diplomatic reports and messages, 1937-1939 (Folder 5)
      - Great Britain. Printed copies of diplomatic reports, messages, and parliamentary debates, typescript reports of cabinet meetings, a typescript memorandum by M. Hankey, "The Future of the League of Nations," and a typescript report of a statement by Maxim Litvinov with comments and a draft reply, 1935-1939 (Folder 6-7)
      - Soviet Union. Speeches by Maxim Litvinov and Vyacheslav Molotov, 1938-1939 (Folder 8)
  - World politics, Clippings, printed excerpt, and partial printed transcript of the Nuremberg trials, 1946-1975 (Folder 9)
  - World War, Primarily relates to Spanish involvement in the war. Printed articles and excerpts, 1966-1986, 1939-1945. (Folder 10)
  - Yugoslavia. Bulletins, clippings, and printed articles and excerpts, 1944-1979 (Folder 11)
- SCRAPBOOKS, 1935-1984. (Box 108-112)
  Clippings, serial issues, and typescript memorandum. Arranged alphabetically by serial title.
  - Clippings, serial issues, and typescript copy of a British government memorandum relating to foreign policy, 1935-1984 (Box 108-112)
- MICROFILM, 1932-1949. (Microfilm cabinet, Box 113-114)
  Serial issues and writings. Arranged alphabetically. Detailed list available
  - General. Miscellaneous segments (Box 113-114)
  - Periodicals. NOTE: Most of the dates given below cover broken series
    - A.I.T. Boletin de Informacion, 1937 May 11 (Reel 1)
    - A.I.T. Service de Presse, 1938 March 25-October 5 (Reel 2)
    - Action Francaise, 1936 August 27-28 (Reel 3)
    - Acracia (Reel 4)
      - 1936 October 11-1938 February 11
      - 1936 October 17-1938 March 5 (Reel 5)
    - Adelante (Barcelona), 1934 January 11-March 2
    - Adelante (Mexico City), 1943 June 15 (Reel 6)
    - Adelante (Valencia)
      - 1937 April 8-May 5 (Reel 7)
      - 1937 June 10-20 (Reel 5)
    - Agence Internationale d'Informations, 1938 October-November
    - Ahora, 1936 July 30-August 12 (Reel 8)
    - Al Ataque, 1937 October 25
    - Alba Roja, 1937 June 30-September 30
    - Alianza, 1938 July 10, 26
    - Alliberament (Reel 9)
      - 1937 March 16
      - 1937 June 15 (Reel 8)
    - Amigo del Pueblo, 1937 November 20
    - La Antorcha, 1934 July 24-1936 October 17
    - L'Aube, 1937 May 8-11 (Reel 10)
    - Avancada, 1937 February 20 (Reel 8)
    - Avant, 1936 July 29
    - Az Antifascista, 1937 February 11-March 25
    - Bandera Roja, 1937 May 1
    - Le Barrage, 1937 September 10
    - La Batalla
      - 1932 January 14-1936 September 4
      - 1936 September 5-December 26 (Reel 11)
      - 1936 December 27-1937 May 27 (Reel 12)
      - 1937 July 19-November 27 (Reel 13)
    - Boletin de Informacion, 1937 March-May (Reel 14)
    - Boletin Informativo, 1938 March-October (Reel 13)
    - Boletin Interior del C. E. del POUM, 1937 January 15-April 5
    - The Bulletin, 1936 December
    - C.N.T., 1933 March 8-1938 January 19
    - C.N.T. (Barcelona), 1938 June 4-December 9 (Reel 15)
    - C.N.T. (Madrid), 1936 December 17-1939 April 5 (Reel 16)
    - C.N.T. Maritima, 1937 October 2-1938 February 26
    - C.N.T.-A.I.T.-F.A.I. Boletin de Informacion (Reel 17)
      - 1936 July 2-1937 July 26
      - 1936 August 7-September 19 (Reel 18)
      - 1937 July 27-1938 November 19 (Reel 19)
    - C.N.T.-A.I.T.-F.A.I. Informa Bulteno, 1937 December 10
    - Candide, 1937 August 13-27 (Reel 20)
    - Casa de la Cultura, 1937 August (Reel 19)
    - Castilla Libre
      - 1937 March 28-December 2
      - 1937 August 30-1938 November 26 (Reel 21)
    - Catalunya, 1937 February-August (Reel 19)
    - Ce Soir, 1937 Mary, 8-11 (Reel 22)
    - Claridad (Reel 19)
      - 1935 August 3-1936 March 26
      - 1936 April 7-1938 March 10 (Reel 23)
      - 1936 May 7-1937 October 2 (Reel 24)
      - 1937 March 10-1938 April 15 (Reel 25)
    - Colectivismo, 1938 March 13-December (Reel 26)
    - Le Combat Syndicaliste, 1937 May 21-1939 January 20 (Reel 23)
    - El Combatiente Rojo, 1936 August 24-1937 January 29
    - Comment, 1937 November 13-1939 February 4 (Reel 27)
    - Combat, 1936 November 23
    - El Combate, 1937 March 5 (Reel 28)
    - The Communist International, 1936 December-1937 April (Reel 29)
    - El Comunista, 1936 September 26-1937 June 12 (Reel 27)
    - Contra el Corriente (Mexico City), 1943 May-1944 June (Reel 30)
    - El Correo de Andalucia, 1937 October 20 (Reel 27)
    - La Correspondencia de Valencia, 1936 November 30-1937 October 26 (Reel 31)
    - Cuarta Internacional, 1936 September-1937 December (Reel 27)
    - Cultura Proletaria
      - 1936 November 14-1948 January 24 (Reel 32)
      - 1937 May 29-1939 September 23 (Reel 27)
    - Cultura y Accion
      - 1937 February 18-July 19 (Reel 33)
      - 1937 May 1-1937 August 11 (Reel 27)
    - Daily Herald (London), 1936 October 10-1937 January 30 (Reel 34)
    - Daily Telegraph (London), 1936 November 24-1937 March 24 (Reel 35)
    - El Debate, 1936 March 6-July 17 (Reel 36)
    - La Depeche de Toulouse, 1937 March 1-May 9 (Reel 37)
    - El Dia Grafico (Reel 27)
      - 1936 July 23
      - 1936 October 20-1937 May 6 (Reel 38)
    - Diari de Barcelona
      - 1936 September 27-1937 May 9 (Reel 39)
      - 1936 November 21-December 19 (Reel 27)
      - 1936 December 22-1937 July 15 (Reel 40)
    - Diario de las Sesiones de Cortes, 1936 April 3-October 1 (Reel 41)
    - Diario Oficial del Ministerio de la Guerra (Madrid), 1936 September 1-1937 March 16 (Reel 42)
    - El Diario Vasco, 1939 July 19 (Reel 40)
    - El Diluvio
      - 1936 November 10 (Reel 41)
      - 1937 May 11 (Reel 40)
    - Documentacion Espagnole, 1938 October 8-1939 January 18
    - L'Echo de Paris, 1936 August 4-5 (Reel 44)
    - L'Ere Nouvelle, 1936 October 24-28 (Reel 45)
    - Esfuerzo, 1937 October 14, 24 (Reel 40)
    - L'Espagne Antifasciste
      - 1936 August 22-1937 January 8 (Reel 46)
      - 1936 September 1 (Reel 40)
    - L'Espagne d'Aujourd'hui, 1938 May 15
    - L'Espagne Nouvelle
      - 1937 July 17, 1939 January 15
      - 1937 September 19-1939 June (Reel 47)
    - Espana Expatriada, 1939 August 12-26 (Reel 40)
    - Espana Popular (Mexico City), 1940 March 11-1948 April (Reel 48-50)
    - L'Espurna, 1937 January 23 (Reel 40)
    - Estampa, 1936 October 10
    - F.E. Diario de Falange Espanola, 1936 October 12-1939 June 11 (Reel 51)
    - F.N.E.C., 1936 October 8
    - F.O.N.C., 1937 August
    - Faro, 1937 December 3
    - Faro de Vigo, 1936 September 20-1937 April 2
    - Federated Press Eastern Bureau, 1936 September 8-November 12 (Reel 52)
    - Figaro, 1936 October 23-December 19 (Reel 53)
    - La Fleche (Paris), 1937 September 18 (Reel 54)
    - Fotos, 1939 May 27 (Reel 51)
    - Fragua Social
      - 1937 March 26-1938 September 3 (Reel 55)
      - 1937 March 28-May 4 (Reel 51)
      - 1937 May 5-1938 March 10 (Reel 56)
    - Frente Libertario
      - 1936 October 13-1937 May 6
      - 1936 October 17-1938 April 22 (Reel 57)
      - 1937 May 7-1938 March 12 (Reel 58)
    - Frente Popular, 1937 June 10-November 30
    - Frente Rojo
      - 1937 March 11-December 4
      - 1937 August 26-1939 January 11 (Reel 59)
    - Frente y Retaguardia, 1937 December (Reel 58)
    - Front, 1936 November 29
    - Full Oficial del Dilluns, 1936 August 10-1937 July 19
    - La Gaceta del Norte, 1937 November 9
    - Galicia Libre, 1938 June 30
    - Generacion Hoja, 1937 May (Reel 60)
    - Guerra di Classe, 1937 October 17-November 30 (Reel 58)
    - Giustizia o liberta, 1937 January 20
    - Heraldo de Madrid, 1936 July 15-1937 June 24 (Reel 61)
    - Hoja Oficial del Lunes (Barcelona), 1937 March 22 (Reel 62)
    - La Hora, 1937 June 13 (Reel 61)
    - Horizontes (Mexico City), 1946 November (Reel 63)
    - Hoy (Mexico City), 1937 July 24-1945 January 20 (Reel 64)
    - La Humanitat
      - 1936 July 14-1937 July 6 (Reel 61)
      - 1936 September 30-1939 January 21 (Reel 65)
    - La Humanitat (Barcelona), 1937 April 17-1938 February 18 (Reel 66)
    - L'Humanite (Paris), 1936 August 1-1939 July 12 (Reel 67)
    - I.W.W.A. Bulletin of Information, 1937 June 1 (Reel 68)
    - Ideas (Hospitalet), 1936 December 29-1938 August 27 (Reel 69)
    - L'Independant des Pyrenees Orientales (Perpignan), 1937 May 4-9 (Reel 70)
    - Independent News
      - 1937 October 10-1939 January 12 (Reel 71)
      - 1939 January 12-April 4 (Reel 61)
    - Informationes
      - 1936 July 21-August 5
      - 1936 August 6-September 15 (Reel 72)
    - Informaciones d'Espagne (Paris), 1939 May 17-June 2 (Reel 73)
    - Information Bulletin of the P.O.U.M., undated and, 1936 September 22 (Reel 74)
    - Inquietud, 1937 May-July (Reel 72)
    - L'Instant, 1936 August-November
    - L'Insurgent, 1937 June 26
    - Jeune Garde (Paris), 1937 October 16 (Reel 75)
    - Je Suis Partout (Paris), 1936 December 5 (Reel 76)
    - Le Jour (Paris), 1936 July 27-September 25 (Reel 77)
    - Le Journal de Barcelone (Paris), 1937 March 18 (Reel 78)
    - Journal des Debats (Paris), 1936 July 1-December 31 (Reel 79-80)
    - Juliol, 1936 October 18, 1937 June 19 (Reel 81)
    - Juventud (Paris), 1936 November 13 (Reel 82)
    - Juin 36 (Paris), 1937 January 20 (Reel 83)
    - El Liberal, 1936 September 17-October 15 (Reel 84)
    - La Libertad
      - 1936 January 15-16, 1937 October 9 (Reel 85)
      - 1936 February 16-July 19 (Reel 86-87)
      - 1936 June 28-1937 May 9 (Reel 84)
    - Le Libertaire
      - 1937 April 8 (Reel 88)
      - 1939 January 19 (Reel 84)
    - El Libertario, 1932 December-1933 April 1 (Reel 89)
    - La Lutte Ouvriere
      - 1936 May 16, 1937 May 14 (Reel 84)
      - 1936 August 15-1938 December 16 (Reel 90)
      - 1936 August 22-1937 December 23 (Reel 91)
    - El Magisterio Espanol, 1937 December 11 (Reel 84)
    - Mar y Tierra, 1937 May 29-1938 January 1
    - Le Matin (Paris), 1936 October 18-19 (Reel 92)
    - El Matutino, 1938 February 4 (Reel 84)
    - Los Marxistas, 1935 December 5
    - El Mercantil Valenciano
      - 1936 May 16-1937 May 7 (Reel 93)
      - 1938 July 13 (Reel 84)
    - Mujeres Libres, 1937 August 9
    - Mundo Obrero
      - 1936 January 2-September 24
      - 1936 September 25-1937 November 7 (Reel 94)
      - 1937 July 27, August 18 (Reel 95)
    - Mundo Obrero (Toulouse, Paris), 1946 February 16-1947 April 10 (Reel 96)
    - The New Leader (London), 1937 May 21-June 4 (Reel 97)
    - News Bulletin of the International Brigades, 1937 July 23-1937 September 30 (Reel 72)
    - 19 de Julio (Mexico City), 1941 December (Reel 98)
    - La Noche, 1936 September 17-November 10 (Reel 94)
    - Nosotros
      - 1937 February 11-March 31 (Reel 99)
      - 1937 April 1-December 3 (Reel 94)
      - 1937 April 2, November 22-23 (Reel 100)
    - El Noticiero Universal
      - 1936 July 29-October 23 (Reel 94)
      - 1936 October 24-1937 July 19 (Reel 101)
    - Las Noticias
      - 1936 July 19-October 24
      - 1936 October 25-1937 July 31 (Reel 74)
      - 1938 December 10-1939 January 13 (Reel 102)
    - Nueva Galicia, 1938 April 25 (Reel 74)
    - Nuestra Espana, 1938 April 22-1939 February 10
    - Nuevo Aragon, 1937 January 30
    - Nueva Espana Antifascista [also La Nouvelle Espagne Antifasciste], 1937 September 30-1938 February 24
    - El Obrero de la Tierra, 1936 May 30 (Reel 103)
    - L'Oeuvre (Paris), 1936 October 24-May 11 (Reel 104)
    - El Pais, 1941 February 13, 17 (Reel 74)
    - El Parapete, 1937 August 7, September 4
    - Pasaremos, 1936 December 31-1937 May 8 (Reel 105)
    - El Pensamiento Navarro, 1939 June 1, August 27 (Reel 74)
    - El Pla de Bages, 1937 November 27-December 1
    - Politica (Reel 74)
      - 1936 July 19-1937 April 19
      - 1936 October 1-2, 1937 May 6 (Reel 106)
      - 1936 November 17-1937 May 20 (Reel 107)
      - 1937 May 25-1938 January 1 (Reel 108)
    - Le Populaire (Paris), 1936 September 8-1937 September 11 (Reel 109)
    - P.O.U.M. Informationen, 1937 April 15 (Reel 74)
    - El Productor, 1937 November 20 (Reel 110)
    - La Protesta, 1937 July
    - La Publicitat
      - 1936 July 19-1937 February 13, June 20
      - 1937 February 14-1937 July 20 (Reel 111)
      - 1937 March 28, 30 (Reel 112)
    - Pueblo, 1935 August 10-1936 February 8 (Reel 111)
    - La Rambla, 1936 August 6-1937 May 12
    - Regeneracion, 1937 June 18-1938 March 15
    - Renovacion (Mexico City), 1945 December 25, February 25 (Reel 113)
    - La Republique (Paris), 1936 October 8-9 (Reel 114)
    - La Revista Blanca, 1936 July 15 (Reel 115)
    - La Revolution Espagnole, 1936 September 3-1937 May 1 (Reel 116)
    - La Revolution Proletarienne (Paris), 1936 July-1939 June (Reel 117)
    - Ruta, 1937 February 18-September 26 (Reel 111)
    - Servicio Espanol de Informacion, 1937 September 15-1938 April 24 (Reel 118)
    - S.I.A., 1939 January 19
    - El Sindicalista, 1937 May 5 (Reel 119)
    - El Socialista (Madrid) (Reel 118)
      - 1936 January 14-August 1
      - 1936 August 4-1937 April 28 (Reel 120)
      - 1936 October 26-1937 November 30 (Reel 121)
      - 1937 April 29-1938 March 23 (Reel 122)
    - El Socialista (Toulouse), 1944 November 16-1946 April 9 (Reel 123)
    - El Sol
      - 1936 February 19-July 19 (Reel 124)
      - 1936 August 21-October 22 (Reel 122)
    - Solidaridad Obrera (Barcelona)
      - 1933 March 4-1936 June 7
      - 1936 June 9-October 6 (Reel 125)
      - 1936 October 7-December 24 (Reel 126)
      - 1936 December 25-1937 March 16 (Reel 127)
      - 1937 March 17-May 11 (Reel 128)
      - 1937 July 27-1938 March 22 (Reel 129)
      - 1938 November 27-1939 January 7 (Reel 130)
    - Solidaridad Obrera (Buenos Aires), 1936 December 11 (Reel 131)
    - Solidaridad Obrera (Paris), 1944 February 10-1945 May 6 (Reel 132)
    - Sombrador, 1936 November 29-1937 May 16 (Reel 133)
    - Die Soziale Revolution
      - 1937 January-June (Reel 130)
      - 1937 March (Reel 134)
    - Spain, Press releases by the Spanish Embassy, Washington, D.C. (Reel 130)
    - Spain and the World
      - 1937 June 4 (Reel 135)
      - 1937 October 27-November 24 (Reel 130)
    - Spain Today, n.d.
    - Spanish Information Service, 1938 January 7-April 15
    - Spanish Labor Bulletin, 1939 January 9
    - Spanish Labor News, 1937 November 9-1938 April 2
    - Spanish News Service, 1937 June 9-November 27
    - Spanish Press Agency, 1938 January 9-1939 February 10
    - Spanish Revolution, 1936 August 19-1938 February 25
    - Spanish Revolution (New York), 1937 January 8, February 8 (Reel 136)
    - Die Spanische Revolution, 1937 January, May (Reel 137)
    - Sunday Times (London), 1936 December 6-1937 May 9 (Reel 138)
    - Superacion, 1937 March 12, 19 (Reel 139)
    - De Syndicalist, 1937 June 12-1938 February 26 (Reel 133)
    - Le Temps (Paris), 1937 May 7-April 12 (Reel 140)
    - El Tiempo, 1941 February 21 (Reel 133)
    - La Tierra, 1933 February 24-1937 November 27
    - Terra Lliure, 1936 December
    - Tierra y Libertad
      - 1933 February 24-1938 January 15
      - 1937 March 27-1938 March 26 (Reel 141)
      - 1938 August 6 (Reel 142)
    - Toronto Daily Star (Toronto), 1936 September 1-21 (Reel 143)
    - La Tribuna, 1941 January 25-February 10
    - Treball
      - 1936 July 29-October 1
      - 1936 October 16-1937 October 28 (Reel 144)
    - Ultima Hora, 1936 July 22-December 28
    - Umbral
      - 1937 August 28
      - 1938 March 21-December 24 (Reel 145)
    - Unidad, 1937 May 1, 22 (Reel 146)
    - Unser Wort, 1937 February (Reel 145)
    - La Vanguardia
      - 1936 April 9-October 15 (Reel 147)
      - 1936 October 16-1937 January 28 (Reel 148)
      - 1937 January 29-1937 June 20 (Reel 149)
      - 1937 June 22-November 28 (Reel 150)
      - 1937 November 30-1939 January 31 (Reel 151)
      - 1938 October 27 (Reel 152)
    - La Vanguardia Espanola
      - 1939 February 5-1939 July 20
      - 1939 July 21-September 23 (Reel 153)
    - La Vanguardia Postal, 1938 May 1
    - La Verdad (Reel 153)
      - 1935 August 15-1937 August 24
      - 1936 December 1-1937 January 31 (Reel 154)
    - La Veu de Catalunya
      - 1936 July 29-November 8 (Reel 153)
      - 1936 November 10-1937 January 7 (Reel 155)
    - Via Libre (New York), 1940 May 15-July 19 (Reel 156)
    - Vida, 1938 November 19 (Reel 157)
    - Vida Nueva, 1937 April 8 (Reel 158)
    - La Voce Republicana, 1949 March 23, 27 (Reel 159)
    - La Voix Libertaire, 1937 May 22, 1938 December (Reel 155)
    - La Voz, 1936 August 20-October 21
    - La Voz (New York), 1939 March 26 (Reel 160)
    - La Voz de Madrid, 1937 July 18 (Reel 155)
    - La Voz Leninista, 1937 April 5 (Reel 155)
  - Speeches and writings by others
    - Abad de Santillan, Diego, 1938 (Reel 161)
    - Alvarez, Segis, 1937? (Reel 162)
    - Araquistain, Luis, n.d. (Reel 163)
    - Ardiaca, Pedro, n.d. (Reel 164)
    - Asensio, Jose, n.d. (Reel 165)
    - Aviles, Gabriel, 1939 (Reel 166)
    - Azaretto, Manuel, 1939 (Reel 167)
    - Barca, J. O., 1937 (Reel 168)
    - Baraibar, Carlos de, 1935 (Reel 169)
    - Barrio, Josep del, 1937 (Reel 170)
    - Bergamin, Jose, 1944 (Reel 171)
    - Brailsford, H. N., 1937 (Reel 172)
    - Brenner, Anita, 1937 (Reel 173)
    - Caballe i Clos, T., 1939 (Reel 174)
    - Camps i Arboix, Joaquin de, 1935 (Reel 175)
    - Cambo, Francisco, n.d. (Reel 176)
    - Carney, William P., 1937 (Reel 177)
    - Carrillo, Santiago, 1937 (Reel 178-179)
    - Challaye, Felician, 1938 (Reel 180)
    - Colome, Victor, 1938 (Reel 181)
    - Colvin, Ian D., 1938 (Reel 182)
    - Curtiss, John S., n.d. (Reel 183)
    - Dennis, Lawrence, 1937 (Reel 184)
    - Fernsworth, Lawrence A., 1936-1938 (Reel 185)
    - Gannes, Harry, 1936 (Reel 186)
    - Garcia Pradas, J., 1937-1938 (Reel 187-188)
    - Goebbels, Joseph, 1937 (Reel 189)
    - Gomez Hidalgo, F., 1935 (Reel 190)
    - Heras, Antonio, 1936 (Reel 191)
    - Horsefall Carter, W., 1936 (Reel 192)
    - Hernandez, Jesus (Reel 193)
    - Iniesta, Juan de, 1937 (Reel 194)
    - Iribarron, Jose Maria, 1938 (Reel 195)
    - Johnston, G. R., 1939 (Reel 196)
    - Koltzov, M., n.d. (Reel 197)
    - Krehm, William, n.d. (Reel 198)
    - Lacruz, F., 1943 (Reel 199)
    - Laird, Megan, 1936 (Reel 200)
    - Langdon Davies, John, 1938 (Reel 182)
    - Leval, Gaston, 1938 (Reel 201)
    - Lewandowski, Maurice, 1940 (Reel 202)
    - Lindley, Ernest K. and Weintal, Edward, 1944 (Reel 203)
    - Llado i Figueras, J., 1938 (Reel 204)
    - Lopez, Juan, 1937? (Reel 205)
    - Manuel, Frank, 1936 (Reel 206)
    - Martin, J., 1936 (Reel 207)
    - Martinez Barrio, Diego, 1937 (Reel 208)
    - Marty, Andre, 1936-1937 (Reel 209-212)
    - Miralles, Rafael, 1946 (Reel 213)
    - Moran, Catherine, 1932 (Reel 214)
    - Muria, Jo, sep, 1936 (Reel 215)
    - Negre, Jose, 1937? (Reel 216)
    - Oehler, Hugo, n.d. (Reel 217)
    - Oltra Pico, J., 1936 (Reel 218)
    - Palacio, Solano, n.d. (Reel 219)
    - Peers, E. Allison, 1937 (Reel 220)
    - Perdrisat, G., n.d. (Reel 221)
    - Pous i Pages, J., 1937 (Reel 222)
    - Ravage, M. E., 1936 (Reel 223)
    - Rodriguez Vega, Jose, 1937 (Reel 224)
    - Romero, Carlo, n.d. (Reel 225)
    - Rosselli, Carlo, 1937-1938 (Reel 226-227)
    - Roure-Torent, J., 1937 (Reel 228)
    - Rous, Jean, n.d. (Reel 229)
    - Rovira i Virgili, A., 1932-1940 (Reel 230-231)
    - Rubio i Tuduri, Mariano, 1937 (Reel 232)
    - Rudiger, H., 1937 (Reel 233)
    - Ryan, William, 1939 (Reel 234)
    - Sanchez Barbudo, Antonio, 1938 (Reel 235)
    - Sartin, Max, 1938 (Reel 236)
    - Silva, Jose, n.d. (Reel 237)
    - Stimson, Henry L., et al., 1939 (Reel 238)
    - Tarradellas, Jo, sep, 1938 (Reel 239)
    - Tasis i Marca, Rafael, 1937 (Reel 240)